I'm going to call it all over the way for me, the Miami City Council for today's date and time.
Item two is approval of claims.
Staff is recommending that the part of the claims relating to the fire truck is pulled out.
It's going to be discussed later in the agenda.
Yes, sir.
So I would just ask for most approval of the claim with the exception of the, would you read what that is?
It's just P&C.
It's just what it's listed.
P&C.
Equipment findings, sir.
So do we have a most of your approved claims with the exception of the P&C equipment financing?
Your friends, this is your contract.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's a building.
So we want to talk about it when we talk about that fire truck.
It's just to make sure we take it in the right order.
This is going to be careful about that.
So with that said, do we have a motion to approve claims?
Submit.
And the second please?
All right.
Roll call?
Davis.
Lewis.
Hi.
Western.
All right.
I'm three as a minutes from June 16th, 2020.
Do we have a motion to approve the minutes?
I'll make that motion to do a second.
Okay.
Roll call.
Please.
All right.
Or it?
Lewis.
All right.
Yeah.
Is this clear?
You may be ready.
Well that's the end of the second.
Okay.
And then we can go there.
So that we can go there.
The second.
All right.
Go there.
You may be ready.
All right.
Okay.
So that.
All right.
Well.
I want to say.
that I support O.V. in the Constitution of the United States.
O.V.
Constitution of the United States.
And the Constitution of the State of Oklahoma.
And then I will not knowingly.
And I will not knowingly.
Received from.
Received.
Any money for other valuable things?
Any money or other valuable things?
For the performance or non-performance or non-performance?
Of any act or duty?
Just hanging to my office?
Protecting my office?
Other than the compensation allowed by law?
Of the compensation allowed by law?
I further swear or affirm.
Of the swear or affirm?
Then I will faithfully discharge.
I will faithfully discharge.
That's my duty.
Supporting the rest of my office.
The duty is to my office.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
the mayor of the city of Miami, Central.
I don't think that's the mayor and the school.
And chairman of the Board of Trustees, the...
I chairman of the Board of Trustees.
I don't know about that.
Miami's speciality utility is already.
I'm a speciality utility authority.
I'm a speciality authority.
I don't know about the club.
Can we guys join each of this?
So, pastor for Zell Lepthis?
Yes.
For Lepthis?
I'm not sure what the statute was trying to see now.
It's not for me.
Good luck!
Thank you for coming.
You guys, give her your hand for us.
Start from here with you.
Thank you.
I want to give you a picture.
You can get it.
I remember five public input or unscheduled personal appearances.
On to item number six consent agenda item 713.
Any questions on you?
Hello everyone.
I think I'm going to show you a group.
Second.
Davis or Orquette?
Davis?
Louis?
I'm not going to.
I don't know.
Okay.
Question.
Parker?
Hi.
I'm number 11.
We'll be presentation of GR's GAR Symmeteries New Website.
Kim Horton.
Thanks, bro.
And Fred Miller.
So Nancy's going to get us kind of keyed up.
And we're presenting this tonight as a team.
Because this has been a ten.
Bless you, your team effort.
And not just for our team, but we've had a lot of community volunteers.
There's a few that I want to name.
We had a gentleman about ten years ago that came out to the cemetery for three or four years.
And literally took pictures of every single marker in the cemetery for us.
His name was Christopher Daweson.
And the last year that he was coming out, he got pretty ill.
He was driving more and he would literally drive his bicycle to come out and be this way.
We had three ladies that we adored May and Barbara and May that came out over a two-year period and wrote down every fifth and
smart group in GAR. We had almost 28,000 variables in GAR. We had no idea how many best ones we had.
Judy Francisco was she retired came out and every Tuesday, for over a year, put in burial records.
So this project, tonight we're going to show you where the website that are really started with figuring out how we were going to put in all these
burial records and all these property records, to get to the point where someone all over the world could go on our website and find a loved one.
Amanda had a test of this. The genealogy tourism is huge. People love to go places and, you know, try to find their family.
An hour ago, I had a lady called for Michigan to tell me how much she loves her new website and I said, perfect timing.
So we're just going to do a brief presentation. First of all, I want to say thank you to all those people because we couldn't have done it without them and also the support of
not just sitting in the middle of the council because there was budgetary things involved, but it's been a great investment.
The tree that you see is our symbol. On the south end of the cemetery, that is a railroad. It is not a note that is really
native to Oklahoma. It's a really unique tree. It's over a hundred years old and so we use that kind of this our symbol for GAR.
All the photographs you see are a testament to Nancy who is a very, very gifted photographer
and Gary Crowe who about five or six years ago, we called him to come out for an event and he said, I'll come out for all your events.
I'm not going to charge you anything and you can use all the photographs. So every photo that you pretty much see on the website, you're with Nancy and Gary.
So they're all pretty good. We're going to start and we want to show you just a few of the highlights.
Probably our favorite part is a section of this called Remember My Journey. And what this allows you to do is you can go in and look for your loved one at GAR,
but it also allows you to put obensionaries, pictures, stories, anything you can imagine.
Nancy actually receives it when families have put the information and she approves it. But what it allows us to do is
our goal with this website was we want to interact with families not what they need a mark for raised or something we
did. We want to interact with them and we want to learn the stories of their loved ones. So this is a really neat part of that.
Do you want to show Kenneth Grace back? Sure. So I typed in Kenneth Grace back's name. He's one of our cadets that are very
out here in our British plot. As you can see.
The variety type in is name.
It brought up his file right here, but it also
pents him on the Google map.
So you can also get directions, walking directions,
or driving directions, as to how to get to that specific grade.
A lot of the grades are in a general area.
They're panned in a general area,
because we haven't went in and fine-tune those pens.
That's going to take a little bit of time,
but we will be working on that.
So you click on his name and it brings him up.
Now, if you had something to add to him,
you would just click on the view and submit memories.
As you're entering or submitting these information
pictures, photos, documents, whatever.
If you date them, they will chronologically fall
in order, and they will create a timeline
from the earliest date of the particular document or photograph.
And that's what I've done with Kenneth Raysbeth.
And so I put a little blurb in there that explained
who he is in what the situation was.
And then it goes on to the earliest picture I have a pen,
which is him on a bicycle.
And then it just goes on to the others.
Now, right here, it has a little icon where you can see
whether there's more than one photo or video
in that particular collection.
And then it goes on.
And you can just, where he got married,
you can just follow his timeline, his life.
And then it goes down to where he's in the military station
here at the British Fire's Training School in Miami
during World War II.
And again, he's on his bike, which I thought was kind of cool.
So something special about Kenneth Raysbeth.
We have become very good friends with his son, John.
John never met Kenneth.
His mama's moment to pregnant when he was killed here.
He's been here multiple times.
The last time he was here, he brought a, was it an A-born?
The staff was kind of out of his yard in England.
And we planted it, which is right across
Kenneth Raysbeth from the British Fire, by the Coleman Graves,
because his dad loved to go to the Coleman Theater.
So now we've got his special tree.
So those are the kind of things that this opens up.
There's another section.
I had a quick question.
I should do mine.
So who moderates that?
So if somebody wants to go on and they put in for me,
do you have to moderate what information goes in our means?
Yes, everything's funneled through this cemetery staff,
generally it's me, that the emails do dump into my city website,
or in my city email address.
So I look at everything and I approve it.
I have never had to not approve something.
So yeah, we have both control over what is put in.
I guess for anybody that's done genealogy sometimes there are things that we didn't expect to find.
So, you know, we have that control and it's very clear that we can not put something on there.
And then we have a section called News that Advanced, Nancy Stone, a really good job on this.
We do accordingly Newsletter, so we have all of our Newsletters.
And this is the most recent one, she took that photo, which is just incredible.
You can do all of our newsletters.
You can look at events that we have.
There are images, photos that we take throughout the year, different different seasons.
This is a great story.
This is a auxiliary, ladies, auxiliary flag.
And I guess this woman's mother had done it for years.
They have lost it.
Nancy basically worked with him.
Eric and Regan Legion to find this flag.
I'm just quite a deal.
Yeah, there were only two left in existence.
They had this particular flag.
So, we were really fortunate that Jim and Ellen Johnston with the American Legion actually went in and purchased both of them.
So, you know, we would have them both.
So, this just kind of gives you an example of what our newsletters look like.
And if you go back, you know, it just shows you what you go into maybe.
Okay.
You know, it's got a declaration removal or British flyers remember it's ceremony.
Ever since we got the Angel of Hope, we do a candlelight ceremony every December.
And then on Memorial Day ceremony, which has been a J.A.R. 4.
We've done a lot of work on it that you can go in and look at, like our legacy history.
If you want to come out and just see all of these different interesting people that we have buried at J.A.R.
We share historical information.
At the end of that, we do have this number on this one.
But we do have a map available at the office that actually pinpoint every single person that's in this tour for them to follow.
Do you want to go into cemetery now?
Sure thing.
So, this is really nice.
Inchanted development helps us with this map.
But what this allows us to do now is people can really zoom in on that section to really find out where a grave is.
You know, when you've got 28,000 burials and you're looking for a grave sometimes it's not an easy task.
So this really helps with that.
And then we also have an area where you can look for available from.
property. So people can actually, you know, sometimes we'll have someone call from out of state that wants to buy
thoughts. And now we have the ability for them to go in and look at what's available and we can talk to them over the
phone to do that. And then last in the contact us, it was really important to us that people be able to see who we are and
know our story. Our motto is family's first and we want to feel very accessible. We want to give good service to our families and so everyone that is on staff at
GAR, the stories there, and people are able to contact us directly. So anything to this? No, I don't think so.
Oh, one thing that we didn't touch on is the actual tours. We have winning and created tours. Now one thing that we didn't have before that we do have now is the availability of putting audio to the tours. So if someone's sitting at home, and they click on, for an example, they click on the values this one.
The British plot. And they don't know anything about it. We could verbally go in and make a recording for them to actually listen to. So that, you know, that's also ADA compliant, also for people that are, you know,
you can see the vision impaired. And you click on each individual one. I'm just going to demo like that, can I?
They all have their photos on here now. I have researched with the help of some other people have researched and obtained photographs of every single cadet that is up here. So, you know, if we find out any information, we can actually upload that.
Can the individuals, as well, go in there and upload like digital stores or all histories of, okay?
Yeah, pretty amazing. I mean, questions? I think to close, we think GAR is sacred ground. It is sacred ground. It's a special place that represents this community and this county.
We also think we have a responsibility that everybody that's very there to tell their life story. It's a celebration of life. And what this allows us to do, I mean, it's almost like little nuggets.
People will call or they'll send us pictures and we get so excited because, you know, friend has probably moved past that mark or a hundred times and wondered about that person and now we're able, better to document those stories that this will be there long after we're going.
So, we just wanted to present it. We wanted the public to see it. And, you know, thank all of you for really budgetary support. I want to give fancy credit.
We worked with Web7Taries. We were one of their first 50 customers 10 years ago when they started business. So, when we got ready to do this, we paid about 40% of what they would start.
someone else because we've been a good customer and then we also pay yearly and get a 10% discount.
So we would like to want you to finish.
So thank you guys very much.
Thank you.
Item 12 except or reject the award of C20-39 fire pumper truck and C20-45 tanker truck to
conrad fire equipment and I think Robert or he found that Chris and Robert and Chris are going
to do that.
Thank you.
Welcome award.
Bless you.
Thank you.
Everyone, thank you for what you do.
I was just counting the award.
So what we are bringing to you is a recommendation to award the contracts for
purchase of a new tanker truck and pumper truck to award that to conrad fire
out of a way to cancel that $340,491.440 and $311.311.320 and $27.80.
I like the first.
I just have several times throughout this process I can't believe what we can.
Two timely is what we received.
There was a minimum consideration in response to solicitations C20-39 and C20-40.
A third bid was received after the bid opening.
But first day at law we cannot consider that bid.
We don't need an opening.
The contractive.
The bidder and destroyed it at the request.
One, Route 66 emergency equipment was present at the bid opening.
But he announced quickly that his bid was not compliant.
The bidder typically waits with a very last minute to try and get all the numbers together
and then just couldn't pull it together.
And so he wanted to be part of the process, but said he was not compliant.
So that left us with Carmichael fire.
We have a good working relationship with Carmichael fire.
It was the fire department that I had considering their proposal.
So we, the fire department that we use that.
But that brings us to here to present that to me for consideration and recommendation to avoid.
Chris, could you talk about the 5% just though there's clarity on that?
Sure.
So you'll see that there is a solid number with a request for a 5%.
flexibility. That's really not going to come in to play here. We're pretty certain of that.
When you're dealing with a dealership, whether you're buying a car or even a fire truck,
they submit their bills with the caveat that says, this is our price unless someone buys it,
before you can commit, before we can say, hey, we've got an approved contract award.
So with that they ask for 5% flexibility for those numbers, because they're going to have to pull another piece of equipment.
Hopefully, I get to go to what we've asked for actually it has to be because it has to be dispatched,
so that there's solicitation.
So that's that reasoning for the 5%.
But we confirmed these numbers yesterday.
And if it's awarded tonight, we really don't think the 5% is going to come into play.
They are selling trucks, hot and heavy according to the dealership,
that's coming out of COVID, everyone's ready to start buying in,
and the manufacturers are actually manufacturing.
So if we award it tonight, we're going to send them a letter basically saying,
on letterhead saying, hey, this is going to work.
It should help that truck, those trucks until we're ready to get them to check.
Does that answer your questions about the 5%.
It's very unusual.
Don't give that.
But I don't know, Tyler, I was going over everything today,
and I saw that the fire trucks on there and kind of had a little panic attack.
I'm just getting on here, and I want me to prove eight hundred thousand dollars for the trucks.
You know, and not even know anything about them yet.
So Tyler, that's several conversations today.
And so basically this is leasing two trucks that are going away,
and we're going to release two in their place.
We're just two of them that we had.
I'm going to believe in payment.
We're sending one of the trucks back.
We're keeping one and then releasing the two payments.
Keep them in the latter.
And try.
The engine three in 2014 and 18.
We spent $15,000 on it.
You may be driving it down the road.
It goes and let them away to the emergency call.
So because of the issue, it was the first year that everything was totally like trying.
So with the issues we've had with that we've decided to.
Brother Mike.
I'm going to return it.
I'm going to.
Latter.
And give us an engine in the place our tanker.
Right.
By the way, we had two we were releasing.
We want we release them.
Those getting more.
We're releasing.
We're releasing two more.
Yes.
All right.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Can you explain the two options to me, please?
One, there's a $4,000 difference in the two options.
Between the 300,000 and 311,000?
No, on the here frame liner tanker.
We do a pre-convenient discount for option one.
There's a $4,000 thing.
That's a discount to pre-pay and full to buy the truck outright
with a single check.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And just so everyone's clearing the mayor.
And I don't discuss this.
So, you know, if it's awarded tonight, we'll award it.
And then staff will work on getting financing.
And we'll present financing at the next meeting to least these trucks.
And we're from five to ten years.
The previous one's released for ten years.
So, we'll have that at the next meeting.
And thank you to also add the combat fire.
It offers us a least payment option also.
So, that would probably be the amount that we would use if we least would.
Okay, thank you.
And staff is comfortable with the way it's played out.
They're not being really any competition at the bidding table.
And it's not really in peerless manufacturing.
But it's only the top fire truck apparatus manufacturers.
We've been playing with her trucks.
We've got an 89 peer so it's a county truck that we don't have any trouble with.
But it's before the days of electronics and every place manual.
You know, the prime of the truck.
You know, there were things cables.
And that's an 1989.
We'll go anywhere.
I'd ask a comment or question earlier.
What do you go to pick a truck?
Is that like a committee of part of your fireman?
And you guys, I mean, how do you guys decide on what truck to do?
Well, what we've done in the past is we've had a committee because we got a custom truck like a new one.
You build it from the ground up.
You know, when you pick what you want to own it.
This time we decided to go with a conventional cab truck,
which is like a freight liner,
that we can take a job, letting it work done.
When we've worked on this, when we put three throttle body sensors in there,
400 bucks from here is just for the part.
And then you've got to get it put on.
But for like a freight liner, it's 100 bucks.
And you can take it to a freight liner and it'll fix it.
So this is a truck that is, you know, it's one that they may regularly put out.
It's not a custom truck.
But we did have input and folks were out where people could look at them.
And we didn't make a couple of changes because of that.
Now, when you say it's like a freight liner, is it going to have the...
Long nose on the front end, there's a extent of me to know the Custard, but it's gonna have the longer nose. Actually, the tribe has a truck just exactly like this, just right now that they respond over here with, and it's got the longer nose on it, it's not flat with the wheels on the top.
So I won't have any trouble like in our city streets and find the order to anything.
You know, it would be like a done truck, and I've talked to the tribe and they've indicated they come over and we have a search for it, and they don't have any problems getting around the city streets.
Mr. Babes, maybe they have to get personal or clearly, when we go out for then, that is a 20-day minimum, that's minimum, that we have to give all of our vendors an opportunity.
To respond, and we have a vendor list, so we sent out this list of patients to many vendors.
I feel confident they were all aware, all have the same opportunities.
Unfortunately, one was a procrastinator, I think he had done big at any time, so that happens.
Jill, I just, I have a more question.
Okay, you go ahead and take a look.
Hey, Tyler, is this in our budget?
That's what's my question.
I can answer this about Jill, Jill's dying to answer it so on.
So, in the budget, in during the budget sessions, we talked about that if tonight's not approved, we have to pay the blind payment.
The full blind payment on both trucks on the 16th of September of July, sorry.
And that's $2,33,997.
So we budgeted the worst case scenario in a highest number, just in case, but we're anticipating you to approve tonight's award a bit.
Which means we'll pay only the blind on one truck and the other one will go back and then we'll come back to you next month with financing for the other two trucks, the two new trucks.
The financing for the two new trucks, plus the one blind payment we're going to make is going to be less than the 233,000 with it.
We have budgeted.
Yeah, that's why we pulled out that claim just to, so we approve a blind payment.
Yeah, to explain that.
You have the questions?
We'll make the motion to approve.
And the client.
Okay, we'll do, we'll do, we'll need to do them separately.
Yes, we'll do them separately.
Yes, sir.
We'll do them separately.
This is for the two new trucks.
Yes, sir.
So I'm a second.
Davis.
Hi.
Work it.
All right.
Lewis.
Winston.
Five.
Parker.
All right.
So now we'll talk about.
It's not on her.
It's the last year.
There's a goal of the claim for the paying of the public pay.
I think I'm on one.
I'm not trying to send the other one back.
Yes, sir.
And that would lower that.
You know, I mean, I have the number.
It's 146.
144.
146,000.
$650.
$660.
And $650.
Yeah.
So if you just approved that.
No.
Everybody had any questions.
Before we move on on that one.
So motion.
And I have my question to pay off.
The blue one.
And send it a little bit.
Okay.
That might be in your.
All for here.
Lewis.
I.
Winston.
All right.
Davis.
Work it.
All right.
Parker.
Thank you.
We want to 13.
We want to 13 other new business.
If any.
All right.
So 14 staff reports.
Those are in the packet.
So that's for any of the council members to ask questions about any of those reports.
Okay.
And 15 mayor and council community announcements.
So we had a man football come up.
We talked about that a long ago.
On the 18th.
And the man does a great job of that.
So that's.
Yeah.
Also, you got Saturday.
Turn it.
Sorry.
So.
You took a 14.
Friday.
Eight minutes.
Just chicken Saturday.
And then.
The following.
Wednesday.
We have to wear baseball.
Which were one and 12 fights.
And reach.
So.
He does.
He should be far.
Most of the time.
He does.
He should be far.
Yeah.
Cool.
And the other.
And 16.
In terms of the manager's communication.
Yes.
So the only thing I have is this week.
And they are starting on Main Street.
You should see them later on towards it.
This week.
We start with an equipment.
There will be out there surveying.
Getting their elevations and everything.
So we will be started on that.
We're excited.
You know.
We would like to thank.
I mean, we.
Oh, dot.
We do have a.
Almost.
I have to make another tap grant that we got on that project.
it's $166,000, I'm right in there so that we have for the project, you know, we have the
city side funding stuff and MSU-A side funding stuff, we borrow money to fix the stormwater
in front of the Coleman there, so there'll be a really neat project when it's done.
How long do I need to just wait that?
December, our kind of their schedule they gave us would be around the end of December, the
mid-in-is December, that's with good weather, everything so.
Oh, look at the board of laughter, starting in the intersection of first.
Yes, they're starting right there at the Coleman, so that's the stormwater area that
they're replacing, so they want to start there first, because they're going to take
it all the road, take down the storm cranes, put bigger storm cranes in.
Is that the area that's already, I know right there in front of the yard?
Yes, that's right.
And so we are actually going back, if you notice, there's some area that thanks to
did not take in in front of like the new facility there, we're going to have new sidewalks
there, we'll have new asphalt there, where we put the new water line in, there's the rock area right
there, so we'll be getting that in a little bit of a new asphalt and everything, so.
The intersection, it's not on that side, it takes the intersection, but they just managed
coming off the dirt road on the main street, so that's nice, right there, so that's nice.
Very nice.
Lots of positive feedback about that, it drains good now and so.
I should not take the lead.
All right, the number 17 adjourned.
Second.
Davis, work it.